Every Time, Every Year.
On Halloween is a horror, thriller film directed by Timothy Boyle.
A journalist goes in search of the truth after a series of brutal deaths and disappearances lead back to an urban
legend about a serial killing clown that has stalked the woods of Century Park for over a hundred years.
Jordan, played by Giselle van der Wiel.
Boo, played by Telen Rodwell.
Jimmy, played by Aaron J. March.
Carl, played by Robert Harrell.
Ethan, played by James Pratt.
Marc, played by Daniel Musial.
Halloween is a 2018 American slasher film and the eleventh
installment in the Halloween film series.
It is a sequel to Halloween (1978), ignoring the events
of every other film in the franchise.
The film was directed by David Gordon Green, who co-wrote
it with Jeff Fradley and Danny McBride.
The film stars Jamie Lee Curtis reprising her role as Laurie Strode.
James Jude Courtney portrays Michael Myers, with Nick Castle
returning to the role for a cameo appearance.
Halloween also stars Judy Greer, Andi Matichak, Will
Patton, Haluk Bilginer, and Virginia Gardner.
Its plot follows a post-traumatic Laurie Strode who prepares to face an escaped Michael Myers in a
final showdown on Halloween night, forty years after she survived his killing spree.
After the release of Rob Zombie's Halloween II, the 2009 sequel to the 2007 remake of the original, two consecutive follow-ups
went into development from former rights holder Dimension Films, respectively, but neither came to fruition.
As a result, the studio lost the rights to the intellectual property, which were later
obtained by Blumhouse Productions with John Carpenter's involvement.
Carpenter, who disagreed with the remake's portrayal of lead killer Michael Myers, planned on helping the studio to
make the next Halloween film into what he believed to be more terrifying than the preceding sequels.
Filmmakers David Gordon Green and Danny McBride, who were already
fans, proposed their vision to Blumhouse and Carpenter.
It was accepted and developed into a sequel to the original.
Halloween was filmed from January to February 2018 in Charleston,
South Carolina, before reshoots took place that June.
The film premiered at the Toronto International
Film Festival on September 8, 2018.
It was theatrically released in North America on
October 19, 2018, by Universal Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics with praise for Curtis' performance, Green's direction, scares, and
tone, with many deeming it both the best Halloween film since the original and a return-to-form for the series.
It was a box office success, grossing over $259
million worldwide on a $10 million budget.
Halloween is the highest-grossing slasher film in unadjusted dollars, breaking a record that
Scream had previously set in 1996 as well as setting several other box-office records.
The film was followed by two sequels: Halloween
Kills (2021) and Halloween Ends (2022).
The tone is dark and intense.